Guide to the Henry David Gray Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Churches Served, Series II
  - Oneonta Congregational Church, South Pasadena (1942-1955)
    - Bound volumes of church records
      - Treasurer's reports, 1942-1951 (Box 28, Folder vol. 19)
      - "Upward Trails" (PF), 1939-1955 (Box 28, Folder vol. 20)
  - South Congregational Church, Hartford (1955-1971)
    - Alphabetical File
      - Administration (Box 29, Folder 208)
      - Annual meetings (Box 29, Folder 209)
      - Annual reports (Box 29, Folder 210-211)
      - Benevolences (Box 29, Folder 212)
      - Building program - Funding (Box 29, Folder 213-215)
      - Building program - Furnishings/decor (Box 29, Folder 216)
      - Building program - Planning/construction (Box 30, Folder 217-225)
      - Building program - Planning/construction (Box 31, Folder 226)
      - Building program - Landscaping (Box 31, Folder 227)
      - Building program - Photographs (Box 31, Folder 228)
      - Building program - Groundbreaking/cornerstone laying (Box 31, Folder 229)
      - Building program - Dedication of new facilities (Box 31, Folder 230-231)
      - Building program - Problems/adjustments (Box 31, Folder 232)
      - Christian education (Box 31, Folder 233-234)
      - Church business correspondence (Box 31, Folder 235-238)
      - Church Council (Box 32, Folder 239)
      - Church Transfer Account (Box 32, Folder 240-241)
      - Church year program (Box 32, Folder 242)
      - Civic Affairs Committee (Box 32, Folder 243)
      - Clubs (Box 32, Folder 244)
      - Committee on Advance (Box 32, Folder 245-247)
      - Committees - lists (Box 32, Folder 248)
      - Financial records (Box 32, Folder 249)
      - Forward Commission (Box 32, Folder 250)
      - Forward Commission (Box 33, Folder 251)
      - History and description - Guidebooks (Box 33, Folder 252)
      - History and description - Iconography (Box 33, Folder 253)
      - History and description - re. C. Vanarsdalen, former pastor (Box 33, Folder 254)
      - History and description - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 255-256)
      - History and description - 300th anniversary (Box 33, Folder 257)
      - House Committee (Box 33, Folder 258)
      - Installation of HDG (Box 33, Folder 259)
      - Missions program (Box 34, Folder 260)
      - Music program (Box 34, Folder 261)
      - Parsonage (Box 34, Folder 262)
      - Photographs - 1827 building (Box 34, Folder 263)
      - Photographs - for 1970 guidebook (Box 34, Folder 264-266)
      - Photographs - miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 267-268)
      - Planning documents (Box 34, Folder 269)
      - Procedure manuals (Box 35, Folder 270)
      - Property acquisition (Box 35, Folder 271)
      - Property management (Box 35, Folder 272)
      - Renovations of basement (Box 35, Folder 273)
      - Rules and polity (Box 35, Folder 274)
      - Rural Resources Development Program for Jordan (Box 35, Folder 275)
      - Seating Committee (Box 35, Folder 276)
      - Spiritual Growth Committee (Box 35, Folder 277)
      - Staff meetings (Box 35, Folder 278)
      - Summer programs (Box 35, Folder 279)
      - Women's work (Box 35, Folder 280)
      - WSCH - FM Radio - By-laws, annual reports (Box 35, Folder 281)
      - WSCH - FM Radio - Committee/financial records (Box 35, Folder 282)
      - WSCH - FM Radio - Correspondence/publicity (Box 35, Folder 283)
      - WSCH - FM Radio - Program listings (Box 35, Folder 284-285)
      - Youth work (see Series IV)
    - Bound volumes
      - Annual reports, 1955-1959 (Box 36, Folder vol. 21)
      - Annual reports, 1961-1964 (Box 36, Folder vol. 22)
      - Annual reports, 1962-1966 (Box 36, Folder vol. 23)
      - Annual reports, 1967-1969 (Box 36, Folder vol. 24)
      - Prudential Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 36, Folder vol. 25)
      - Prudential Committee, 1957 (Box 36, Folder vol. 26)
      - Prudential Committee, 1958 (Box 36, Folder vol. 27)
      - Prudential Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder vol. 28)
      - Prudential Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 36, Folder vol. 29)
      - Prudential Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 36, Folder vol. 30)
      - Prudential Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 36, Folder vol. 31)
      - Prudential Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder vol. 32)
      - Business Committee, 1955-1958 (Box 37, Folder vol. 33)
      - Business Committee, 1958-1960 (Box 37, Folder vol. 34)
      - Business, 1956-1959 (Box 37, Folder vol. 35)
      - Business, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder vol. 36)
      - Business, 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder vol. 37)
      - Business, 1964-1966 (Box 37, Folder vol. 38)
      - Business, 1967-1970 (Box 37, Folder vol. 39)
      - Administration, 1961-1962 (Box 37, Folder vol. 40)
      - Staff, 1955-1956 (Box 37, Folder vol. 41)
      - Staff, 1956-1958 (Box 37, Folder vol. 42)
      - Staff, 1958-1968 (Box 37, Folder vol. 43)
      - Church year, 1956-1960 (Box 38, Folder vol. 44)
      - Church year, 1963-1971 (Box 38, Folder vol. 45)
      - Forms, 1956-1960 Feb (Box 38, Folder vol. 46-50)
      - Forms, 1960 May-1963 Aug (Box 39, Folder vol. 51-57)
      - Forms, 1964 Mar-1970 Aug (Box 40, Folder vol. 58-62)
      - "The South Church Courier", 1955-1960 (Box 40, Folder vol. 63-67)
      - "The South Church Courier", 1960-1970 (Box 41, Folder vol. 68-77)
      - Pilgrim Fellowship (See also Series IV), 1956-1970 (Box 41, Folder vol. 78-79)
      - "The Weathervane" (PF), 1956-1958 (Box 41, Folder vol. 80)
      - "South Church Story", 1955-1960 (Box 41, Folder vol. 81-84)
      - "South Church Story", 1961-1962 (Box 42, Folder vol. 85-86)
  - Later churches
    - Hollywood Congregational Church (Interim), 1971 (Box 104, Folder 765)
    - Congregational Church of the Valley (Interim), 1971-1972 (Box 42, Folder 286)
- The Christian Year, Series III
  Following the book Waymarks, which begins this Series, there are three sequences of files:
  A. General planning and source material
  B. Sequence of notes and source material
  C. Second sequence of notes and source material
  - Waymarks by HDG - devotional readings for the Christian Year (Box 43, Folder 287)
  - General Planning and Source Material
    - Drafts for HDG writings (Box 43, Folder 288-291)
    - "Bicentennial Christian Year" (Box 43, Folder 292)
    - Collected material (Box 43, Folder 293)
    - Music, lectionary (Box 43, Folder 294-295)
    - Plan Book and Calendar for the Church Year, 1962-1963: Publications Commission, NACCC (Box 44, Folder 296)
    - Prayers (Box 44, Folder 297)
  - Sequence of notes and source material
    - 1. As the church year begins (Box 44, Folder 298)
    - 2. For all the saints (Box 44, Folder 299)
    - 3. Advent (Box 44, Folder 300)
    - 4. Christmas (Box 44, Folder 301)
    - 5. Epiphany and after (Box 44, Folder 302)
    - 6. Pre-Lenten weeks (Box 44, Folder 303)
    - 7. The Lenten season (Box 44, Folder 304)
    - 8. Holy Week and Eastertide (Box 44, Folder 305)
    - 9. The great forty days of expectation (Box 44, Folder 306)
    - 10. The consecration of the common life (Box 44, Folder 307)
    - 11. Fruits of the Spirit (Box 44, Folder 308)
  - Second sequence of notes and source material
    - Creation season (Box 44, Folder 309)
    - Providence season (Box 44, Folder 309)
    - General (Box 44, Folder 310)
    - Church giving/Every member canvasses (Box 45, Folder 311-315)
    - Thanksgiving (Box 45, Folder 316)
    - Advent/Incarnation season - General (Box 45, Folder 317-318)
    - Advent/Incarnation season - Oneonta Congregational Church (Box 45, Folder 319-320)
    - Advent/Incarnation season - South Congregational Church (Box 46, Folder 321-322)
    - Advent/Incarnation season - College Sunday (Box 46, Folder 323)
    - Proclamation/Epiphany season - Youth activities (Box 46, Folder 326)
    - Presentation season - Annual meetings - Oneonta (Box 46, Folder 324)
    - Presentation season - Annual meetings - South Cong. Ch. (Box 46, Folder 325)
    - Preparation season - General planning and source material (Box 46, Folder 327)
    - Preparation season - First Congregational Church, South Hadley (Box 46, Folder 328)
    - Preparation season - Oneonta Cong. Ch. (Box 46, Folder 329)
    - Preparation season - South Cong. Ch. (Box 46, Folder 330)
    - The Great Week - General planning and source material (Box 46, Folder 331-332)
    - The Great Week - Photographs: Holy Week in Art (Box 47, Folder 333)
    - The Great Week - Photographs: The Holy Land (Box 47, Folder 334)
    - The Great Week - Photographs: Easter drama (Box 47, Folder 335)
    - The Great Week - Loose-leaf notebook (Box 47, Folder 336)
    - The Great Week - Oneonta Cong. Ch. (Box 47, Folder 337-338)
    - The Great Week - Oneonta Cong. Ch. (Box 48, Folder 339-340)
    - The Great Week - South Cong. Ch. (Box 48, Folder 341-343)
    - Fellowship season (Box 48, Folder 344)
    - Personal Witness season (Box 48, Folder 345)
    - World Mission season (Box 48, Folder 346)
    - Fulfillment season (Box 48, Folder 347)
- Youth Files, Series IV
  This Series is divided into three sections:
  A. Chronological sequence of files
  B. Topical sequence of files
  C. Congregational programs/publications
  National organizations
  Regional groups
  - Chronological sequence of files
    - Summer conference, Pomona College, 1924 (Box 49, Folder 348)
    - Pomona Leagues, 1928-1930 (Box 49, Folder 349)
    - Center Congregational Church, Hartford, 1930-1931 (Box 49, Folder 350)
    - Asylum Hill Congregational Church, 1931-1933 (Box 49, Folder 351-352)
    - Northfield Conference of Religious Education, 1932,1933 (Box 49, Folder 353)
    - South Hadley Congregational Church, 1936-1939 (Box 49, Folder 354)
    - Northfield Conference of Religious Education, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 355)
    - Conferences, 1937-1939 (Box 49, Folder 356)
    - Massachusetts Pilgrim Fellowship Conference, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 357)
    - Northfield Conference of Religious Education, 1939,1940 (Box 49, Folder 358)
    - Talk notes, 1939-1942 (Box 49, Folder 359)
    - National Council of the Pilgrim Fellowship, 1940 (Box 50, Folder 360)
    - Secretary of Young People's Work and Student Life, 1940-1941 (Box 50, Folder 361)
    - Work camps, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 362)
    - Christian Youth Council of N.A./ National Council of the Pilgrim Fellowship, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 363)
    - Oneonta Congregational Church Pilgrim Fellowship, 1941-1942 (Box 50, Folder 364)
    - Student Commission, So. Calif. Cong. Conf., 1942 (Box 50, Folder 365)
    - Conferences, 1942-1943 (Box 50, Folder 366)
    - Pilgrim Fellowship Conf. for College Students, 1943 (Box 50, Folder 367)
    - Student Commission, So. Calif. Cong. Conf., 1943 (Box 50, Folder 368)
    - Oneonta Cong. Ch. Pilgrim Fellowship, 1943-1952 (Box 50, Folder 369-370)
    - Oneonta Cong. Ch. Ninth Grade Club, 1944-1945 (Box 51, Folder 371)
    - Student Life and Servicemen's Commission,So. Calif. Cong. Conf., 1944-1945 (Box 51, Folder 372)
    - Big Bear Christian Student Conf., 1945 (Box 51, Folder 373)
    - Cong. Christian Student Fellowship, 1945-1946 (Box 51, Folder 374)
    - Oneonta Cong. Ch. Pilgrim Fellowship, 1945-1946 (Box 51, Folder 375)
    - Oneonta Cong. Ch. Ninth Grade Club, 1946-1954 (Box 51, Folder 376)
    - Senior High Summer Camp - So. Calif. Cong. Conf., 1947 (Box 51, Folder 377)
    - Oneonta Cong. Ch. Pilgrim Fellowship, 1947-1948 (Box 51, Folder 378)
    - Oneonta Cong. Ch. Pilgrim Fellowship and Junior High, 1949-1955 (Box 52, Folder 379-384)
    - Youth-of-the-Month Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 53, Folder 385)
    - South Cong. Ch. youth organizations, 1955-1961 (Box 53, Folder 386-394)
    - Northfield Conferences of Religious Education, 1958,1960 (Box 104, Folder 767)
    - South Cong. Ch. youth organizations, 1962-1968 (Box 54, Folder 395-404)
    - South Cong. Ch. youth organizations, 1968-1970,n.d. (Box 55, Folder 405-409)
  - Topical sequence of files
    - Boy-girl relations (Box 55, Folder 410-412)
    - Christian home (Box 56, Folder 413)
    - Church membership (Box 56, Folder 414)
    - Confirmation (Box 56, Folder 415)
    - Interdenominational religious education (Box 56, Folder 416)
    - Juvenile delinquency (Box 56, Folder 417)
    - Recreation/ games (Box 56, Folder 418)
    - Science and religion (Box 56, Folder 419)
    - Youth counseling materials (Box 56, Folder 420-421)
    - Youth counseling materials (Box 57, Folder 422)
    - Youth group program material (Box 57, Folder 423-424)
  - Congregational programs/publications
    - National organizations
      - Congregational Education Society - Young People's Dept., 1926-1937 (Box 57, Folder 425)
      - Congregational Christian Churches - Board of Home Missions, Div. of Christian Education, Young People's Dept., 1938-1951 (Box 57, Folder 426)
      - Congregational Christian Churches - Board of Home Missions, Div. of Christian Education, Dept. of Student Life, 1939-1942 (Box 57, Folder 427)
      - Congregational Christian Churches - Board of Home Missions, Div. of Christian Education, Dept. of Student Life, 1942-1946 (Box 58, Folder 428)
      - Congregational Christian Churches - Dept. of Higher Education, 1948-1949 (Box 58, Folder 429)
      - Congregational Christian Churches National Council, Pilgrim Fellowship,The Pilgrim Highroad, 1938-1941 (Box 58, Folder 430)
      - Congregational Christian Churches National Council, Pilgrim Fellowship,The Pilgrim Highroad, 1942-1947 (Box 59, Folder 431)
      - Congregational Christian Churches - National Council, Pilgrim Fellowship, 1942 (Box 59, Folder 432)
      - Congregational Christian Churches - Youth service projects, 1938-1958 (Box 59, Folder 433)
      - National Association of Congregational Christian Churches - Pilgrim Fellowship: programs, reports, 1960-1969,n.d. (Box 59, Folder 434)
      - National Association of Congregational Christian Churches - Pilgrim Fellowship: Echo of Faith, 1960-1966 (Box 59, Folder 435)
    - Regional groups
      - Massachusetts Pilgrim Fellowship, 1936 (Box 59, Folder 436)
      - Northeast Pilgrim Fellowship, 1958-1966 (Box 59, Folder 437)
      - Pilgrim Fellowship of Southern Calif. and the Southwest, ca.1954 (Box 59, Folder 438)
- Odyssey Files, Series V
  Documentation is available for the following trips abroad:
  1948 Odyssey
  1949 Odyssey
  1952 Odyssey
  1956 Odyssey
  1960 Odyssey
  1961 National Association of Congregational Christian Churches Greece Work Pilgrimage
  1962 Pilgrimage to Europe
  1963 Greece Work Pilgrimage
  1963 Mission Study Tour
  1964 Odyssey
  1966 Pilgrimage to Europe
  1967 Odyssey
  1970 Odyssey
  1977 Odyssey
  There are also files related to two Odyssey reunions.
  - 1948 Odyssey
    - Preparations (Box 60, Folder 439)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 60, Folder 440-442)
    - Participants (Box 60, Folder 443)
    - Logbook (Box 60, Folder 444)
    - Photographs/clippings/student talks (Box 60, Folder 445-448)
    - Letters received by HDG during Odyssey (Box 61, Folder 449)
    - Letters to/from parents of participants (Box 61, Folder 450)
    - Letters of appreciation (Box 61, Folder 451)
    - Follow-up speaking engagements (Box 61, Folder 452)
  - 1949 Odyssey
    - Preparations (Box 61, Folder 453)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 61, Folder 454)
    - Participants (Box 61, Folder 455)
    - Reports of British participants (Box 61, Folder 456)
    - Student talks/reports (Box 61, Folder 457)
    - Bound volume of documentation (Box 61, Folder 458)
    - Photographs/clippings (Box 61, Folder 459)
  - 1952 Odyssey
    - Bound volume of documentation - "The Flying Pilgrims" (Box 62, Folder 460)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 62, Folder 461-462)
    - Accounts (Box 62, Folder 463)
    - Letters received by HDG during Odyssey (Box 62, Folder 464)
    - HDG letters to Oneonta church staff during Odyssey (Box 62, Folder 465)
    - Letters to/from parents of participants (Box 62, Folder 466)
    - Letters of appreciation/response (Box 62, Folder 467)
    - re. Christian Century article criticizing Odyssey group's visit to Cambridge (Box 62, Folder 468)
    - Student talks/reports (Box 62, Folder 469)
    - Photograph album (Box 62, Folder 470)
    - Photographs/clippings (Box 63, Folder 471-472)
    - Follow-up projects (Box 63, Folder 473-474)
    - Follow-up correspondence (Box 63, Folder 475)
  - 1956 Odyssey
    - Bound volume of documentation - "The Flying Pilgrims" (Box 63, Folder 476)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 63, Folder 477-480)
    - Accounts (Box 64, Folder 481)
    - Preparations (Box 64, Folder 482)
    - Participants (Box 64, Folder 483)
    - Photograph album (Box 64, Folder 484)
    - Photographs/clippings (Box 64, Folder 485-486)
    - Diaries of participants (Box 64, Folder 487)
    - Letters received by HDG while on Odyssey (Box 64, Folder 488)
    - Publicity (Box 65, Folder 489)
    - Follow-up projects (Box 65, Folder 490)
    - Follow-up correspondence (Box 65, Folder 491)
  - 1960 Odyssey
    - Bound volume of documentation - "The Flying Pilgrims" (Box 65, Folder 492)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 65, Folder 493)
    - Accounts (Box 65, Folder 494)
    - Preparations (Box 65, Folder 495)
    - Participants (Box 65, Folder 496)
    - Photographs (Box 65, Folder 497)
    - Notes/clippings (Box 66, Folder 498)
    - HDG log, notes, correspondence (Box 66, Folder 499)
    - Publicity (Box 66, Folder 500)
    - Follow-up programs (Box 66, Folder 501)
    - Follow-up correspondence (Box 66, Folder 502)
  - 1961 National Association of Congregational Christian Churches Greece Work Pilgrimage
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 66, Folder 503)
    - Participants (Box 66, Folder 504)
    - Photographs/clippings (Box 66, Folder 505)
    - Letters/reports from Ellen Gray on Pilgrimage (Box 66, Folder 506)
  - 1962 Pilgrimage to Europe
    - Bound volume of documentation (Box 66, Folder 507)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 66, Folder 508)
    - Preparations (Box 66, Folder 509)
  - 1963 Greece Work Pilgrimage
    - Various (Box 66, Folder 510)
  - 1963 Mission Study Tour
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 66, Folder 511)
    - Report (Box 66, Folder 512)
  - 1964 Odyssey
    - Bound volume of documentation (Box 67, Folder 513)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 67, Folder 514)
    - Preparations (Box 67, Folder 515)
    - Participants (Box 67, Folder 516)
    - Photographs/clippings (Box 67, Folder 517-518)
    - Follow-up speaking engagements (Box 67, Folder 519)
    - Follow-up correspondence - Lady Doak College, India (Box 67, Folder 520)
    - Follow-up correspondence - Taiwan (Box 67, Folder 521)
  - 1966 Pilgrimage to Europe
    - Various (Box 68, Folder 522)
  - 1967 Odyssey
    - Bound volume of documentation (Box 68, Folder 523)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 68, Folder 524)
    - Preparations (Box 68, Folder 525)
    - Participants (Box 68, Folder 526)
    - Photographs/clippings (Box 68, Folder 527)
    - Log and notes (Box 68, Folder 528)
    - Follow-up correspondence - Taiwan (Box 69, Folder 529)
  - 1970 Odyssey
    - Bound volume of documentation (Box 69, Folder 530)
    - Accounts (Box 69, Folder 531)
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 69, Folder 532)
    - Preparations (Box 69, Folder 533)
    - Participants (Box 69, Folder 534)
    - HDG log (Box 69, Folder 535)
    - Photographs (Box 69, Folder 536)
  - 1973 Odyssey Reunion
    - Various (Box 69, Folder 537)
  - 1977 Odyssey
    - Itinerary/arrangements (Box 69, Folder 538)
    - Preparations (Box 69, Folder 539)
    - Participants (Box 69, Folder 540)
  - 1981 Odyssey
    - Proposed itinerary (Box 69, Folder 541)
  - 1983 Odyssey Reunion
    - Various (Box 69, Folder 542)
- Writings, Addresses, Sermons, Series VI
  This Series is divided according to genre and format in the following manner:
  A. Sermon notes (topically arranged)
  B. Sermons, addresses, articles
  1. Typescript, 8 1/2" x 11" format (by title)
  2. Pamphlet format (by title)
  3. Published in magazines or newspapers (chronologically arranged)
  C. Prayers, plays, poems (by title)
  D. College and graduate school debates, papers, theses
  E. Diaries, journals, travel memoirs (chronologically arranged)
  F. Related to booklength works (by title)
  - Sermon notes, topically arranged
    - Notes (Box 70)
    - Notes (Box 71)
    - Notes (Box 72)
    - Notes (Box 73)
  - Sermons, addresses, articles
    - Typescript, 8 1/2" x 11" format, by title
      - A - Bl (Box 74, Folder 543)
      - Br (Box 74, Folder 544)
      - By (Box 74, Folder 545)
      - Ca - Conc (Box 74, Folder 546)
      - Cong (Box 74, Folder 547)
      - Cov (Box 74, Folder 548)
      - D - E (Box 74, Folder 549)
      - F - H (Box 74, Folder 550)
      - I - J (Box 74, Folder 551)
      - L - Pa (Box 74, Folder 552)
      - re. Pilgrims (Box 74, Folder 553)
      - Pl - R (Box 74, Folder 554)
      - S (Box 74, Folder 555)
      - T (Box 74, Folder 556)
      - W - Y (Box 74, Folder 557)
    - Pamphlet format
      - By Glory Possessed, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 558)
      - Central Convictions...Daring Deeds, 1955
      - Christians in the Coliseum, 1954
      - The Congregational Way, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 559)
      - The Congregational Witness to the World Today, 1961
      - Four Anchors, 1957
      - From Flaming Vision to Firm Venture, n.d.
      - God's Main Street Garden, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 560)
      - God's Torchbearers, 1970
      - Going Toward Christmas, n.d.
      - The Great Succession in the South Church, 1969
      - Honest to the Churches, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 561)
      - If I Make my Bed in Hell, 1965
      - Life Worthy of Eternity, 1962
      - Jesus in the New Testament, 1980
      - The Mayflower Pilgrims... (see under Booklength works)
      - 964 - 55 - the Real Vote for Real Union, 1957
      - A Path for Returning Exiles, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 562)
      - Primacy of God, 1947
      - Remember the Sabbath Day, 1949
      - The Sense of Vocation, 1947 (Box 75, Folder 563)
      - Some Christian Convictions, 1955
      - Under Orders, 1946
      - What a Modern Church Believes, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 564)
      - What it Means to be a Member of a Congregational Christian Church, 1957-1981
      - Words for Today, 1944
    - Published in magazines or newspapers (see also articles in Pilgrim Highroad, Series IV, Oneonta Messenger, South Church Courier, Series II)
      - Various, 1934-1976, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 565-570)
  - Prayers, plays, poems
    - Can't You Hear, Lord (Box 76, Folder 571)
    - Hollywood Prayers (Box 76, Folder 572)
    - "Unto Us a Son is Given" (Box 76, Folder 573)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 574)
  - College and graduate school debates, papers, theses
    - College honors thesis: "Aimee Semple McPherson", 1930 (Box 76, Folder 575)
    - Seminary thesis: "Paul's Ideas of Life and Death", 1933 (Box 77, Folder 576)
    - Ph.D. thesis: "Antecedents and Meaning of the Modern Evangelical Conception of Grace", 1935 (Box 78, Folder 584)
    - Re. religion (Box 77, Folder 577)
    - Re. history, literature, education (Box 77, Folder 578)
  - Diaries, journals, travel memoirs
    - From college days, 1926-1930 (Box 77, Folder 579)
    - Hartford, Edinburgh, Tubingen, 1930-1935 (Box 78, Folder 579A)
    - "Gray-o-graph" travel journal, 1933-1934 (Box 78, Folder 580)
    - Notes, 1939-1940 (Box 78, Folder 581)
    - Mission tour report, 1963 (Box 78, Folder 582)
    - "Half a Million Miles - Travel with Teenagers", 1973 (Box 78, Folder 583)
    - "Half a Million Miles - Travel with Teenagers", 1973
  - Related to booklength works
    - Bluebook of Congregational Usage (#1,#2,#3 1966-1976) (Box 102, Folder 757)
    - The Christian Doctrine of Grace - drafts, revisions (Box 79, Folder 585)
    - The Christian Doctrine of Grace - publicity, reviews (Box 79, Folder 586)
    - Congregational Usage (see under Bluebook of Congregational Usage)